Jeff Haynes MSc

32 Gleton Avenue Hangleton, Hove BN3 8LL, United Kingdom 01273 888592 (Home) 0777 303 9627 (Mobile) jeff.anthony.haynes@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a data manager & developer with more than eight years of experience. I currently work as a technical data manager for large contract research organization, so I have plenty of experience working well with others as part of a team or agency. I am an enthusiastic and dedicated professional with extensive experience across all areas of database management, design and development. A proactive individual with a logical approach to challenges, I perform effectively even within a highly pressurized working environment. I am quick to grasp new ideas and concepts, and to develop innovative and creative solutions to problems

OBJECTIVE

I am now looking to build on my extensive range of technical skills within a suitably challenging role. I am keen to achieve further professional development

EXPERIENCE

Syneos Health

Clinical Programmer

Lewes, UK

June 2019 – present

Clinical Programmer building and maintaining listings and reports for world-wide major sponsors to deliver clinical trial information on the effectiveness of the trial drugs and systems.

Syneos Health

External Data Manager

Lewes, UK

Aug 2013-June 2019

External Data Manager working with a major global pharmaceutical company and its vendors. I am responsible for the programming, specification building and delivering external data for large EUwide clinical trials.

Sciensus Brighton, UK Nov 2012-

Health Informatics Developer

- Providing Web Reporting Solutions to external clients including Pharmaceutical companies and the **UK NHS**
- ETL (Extract Transform and Load) for migration of dat. from one platform to another.
- Competent .Net Web Programming with regard to integrating reporting controls with web applications
- Using DevExpress industry standard reporting Reports suite
- Production of definitions, Pivot Tables and Charts

Jeff Haynes CV Page 1

- Using Microsoft SQL Server 2005 and its tools to store and retrieve data, create reports (SSRS) and perform data transformations (SSIS)
- Achievements include successfully generating web based reporting of Global Hepatitis and Breast Cancer Audit reports for a large international Pharmaceutical company.

Novartis Pharmaceuticals

Horsham, UK Oct 2006–2012

Safety System Expert

- Responsible for the maintenance of the safety database configuration and change control processes and for the technical support to the business users of safety data tools.
- Providing analysis and queries using SQL and SAS for management decisions leading to Quality Assurance reporting and Correct Action Planning
- Supporting Safety Data Managers and Assistant Safety Data Managers in the retrieval of data from the Safety Database.
- First line operational support to the safety database users.
- Responsible for the configuration and business technical lead for IT projects related to Safety..
- Complete Validation and Testing, Configuration, Deployment and Maintenance of all aspects of Global Drug Safety Systems
- Expert knowledge of the structure and functions of Drug Safety Systems
- Provision of information and support for Health Authority Inspections and CQA internal audits
- Creation and maintenance of reporting and monitoring tools using Oracle, SAS and Visual Basic.
- HTML and CSS skills to allow access to internal data via web browser
- Data migration expertise
- Creation and maintenance of reporting and monitoring tools using Oracle, SAS and Visual Basic.
- Support the deployment and utilization of Electronic Submission of regulatory reports (E2b) functionality to all local Country Pharma Organizations, Affiliates and License Partners to fulfil their regulatory requirements

Covance Cardiac Safety Services

Crawley, UK Feb-Oct 2006

Clinical Data Manager

- Accountable for study data accuracy and timeliness and responsible for the global contact and escalation point between Covance Cardiac Safety Services (CCSS) and their sponsors for all data related activities
- Managing a team of Data Management & Statistics staff within their Clinical Trial Operation team.
- Providing data solutions for existing and future projects for both internal and external customers.
- Maintenance and creation of SAS programs, Visual Basic Scripts, Transact SQL scripts, system testing processes, and all associated documentation.
- Ensuring data management activities performed within the team comply with Covance global quality procedures, Covance SOPs and/or project specific SOPs.
- Assisting in the development and validation of new data management systems and processes.
- Development of detailed reporting/analysis/storage tools for the purposes of quality control and research projects.

Covance Cardiac Safety Services

Data Analyst

Crawley, UK Oct 2004 –Feb 2006

Jeff Haynes CV Page 2

- Responsible for primary liaison between Covance Central Diagnostics and other pharmaceutical company sponsors for all Data Management activities.
- Technical responsibilities also include maintaining/creating SAS programs, Visual Basic Scripts, Transact SQL scripts, and all associated data transfer documentation.
- Developed new tracking system using Access VBA for export delivery and scheduling for multi-centre sites.
- Implemented internal monthly Turn around time metric report for all clients.
- Responsible for client liaison and data delivery and quality control for ECG data exports.
- Successful implementation of a html-based pivot table system for failed faxes for client response and internal monitoring.
- Implemented regular client liaison meetings on a regular basis for all ECG data activities.
- Imparted Knowledge of SQL server automation to team members and provided mentoring to associates.

CP Ships (UK) Ltd

Systems Developer

Crawley, UK Jul 1999–Oct 2004

- Responsible for developing the Companies' new Data Warehouse / OLAP / MIS application holding information relating to revenue, clients and transportation of containers worldwide.
- Provided Microsoft OLAP services for SQL Server 7.0 to produce extended data sets for European
 offices. This information presented to user using web based Pivot Table lists and Excel 2000.
 Additional reporting provided using OLAP MDX SQL, local cubes and Access 2000.
- Responsible for the maintenance of an EDI system using Mercator and Trading Partner products plus
 its VB and SQL server applications to process vessel statistics at each port call and supplying senior
 management with performance and volume information for globally —placed container vessels.
- Successful transition and database administration of centralizing company accounts receivable and accounts payable system

Brighton Health Care

Clinical Effectiveness Coordinator

Brighton, UK

Oct 1994-Jul 1999

Brighton Health Care

Emergency Care Auditor

Brighton, UK

Aug 1992-Oct 1994

BT Plc

Various, UK

Various Commercial and System Auditor Roles

Oct 1980–Aug 1992

EDUCATION

University of Westminster

Masters Degree in Science (MSc), 2001

London, UK

Brighton University

Higher National Certificate in Computer Studies (HND), 1992

Brighton, UK

Brighton University

Brighton, UK

Jeff Haynes CV Page 3

PERSONAL

Date of Birth: 14/10/62 **Languages:** English

Nationality: British Health: Excellent; non-smoker

Driving Licence: Full and Clean

Jeff Haynes CV Page 4